Lesson 16 The modern city
现代城市
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
What is the author's main argument about the modern city?
作者关于现代城市的主要论点是什么?
In the organization of industrial life
在工业生活的组织中,
the influence of the factory upon the physiological and mental state of the workers，
工厂对工人的生理和精神状态的影响,
has been completely neglected.
完全被忽视了.
Modern industry is based on the conception
现代工业的基本概念是:
of the maximum production at lowest cost,
以最低成本获取最多产品,
in order that an individual or a group of individuals,
为的是让某个个人或一部分人，
may earn as much money as possible.
尽可能多地赚钱.
It has expanded without any idea of the true nature of the human beings who run the machines,
现代工业发展起来了,却根本没想到操作机器的人的本质.
consideration: n.  考虑
and without giving any consideration
工厂毫不顾及
descendant: n.  子孙，后代
to the effects produced on the individuals and on their descendants
会给工人及其后代带来何种影响
artificial: n.  人工的, impose: v.  强加
by the artificial mode of existence imposed by the factory.
而把一种人为的生存方式强加给工人.
The great cities have been built with no regard for us.
大城市的建设毫不关心我们.
dimension: n.  直径, skyscraper: n.  摩天大楼
The shape and dimensions of the skyscrapers,
摩天大楼的形状和尺寸，
depend entirely on the necessity of obtaining the maximum income per square foot of ground,
完全取决于每平方英尺地皮取得最大收入，
tenant: n.  租户
and of offering to the tenants offices and apartments that please them.
以及向租房人提供使他满意的办公室和住房这两种需要.
This caused the construction of gigantic buildings,
这样就导致了许多摩天大厦拔地而起,
where too large masses of human beings are crowded together.
大厦内众多的人挤在一起。
Civilized men like such a way of living.
文明人喜欢这样一种生活方式.
luxury: n.  豪华
While they enjoy the comfort and banal luxury of their dwelling,
在享受自己住宅的舒适和庸俗的豪华时,
deprive: v.  剥夺
they do not realize that they are deprived of the necessities of life.
却没有意识到被剥夺了生活所必需的东西.
edifice: n.  大厦
The modern city consists of monstrous edifices,
现代化的城市的组成部分有大得吓人的高楼，
and of dark,narrow streets full of petrol fumes and toxic gases,
和阴暗狭窄、充斥着汽油味和有毒气体的街道,
torn by the noise of the taxicabs,lorries and buses,
街道上出租汽车,卡车,公共汽车的噪音刺耳难忍，
throng: v.  挤满，壅塞
and thronged ceaselessly by great crowds.
络绎不绝的人群挤来挤去。
Obviously,it has not been planned for the good of its inhabitants.
显然,现代化的城市不是为居民的利益而规划的.